#### LEONG XIN HUI

E-mail: xhleong@gmail.com | Phone: +60129130939

Website: <a href="https://xinhui-leong.github.io/">https://xinhui-leong.github.io/</a>



Problem solver that aims at bridging the gap between technology through data driven and creative approaches. Believer that process improvement and innovation needs to take into account the current vitals(data), process, people and technology to identify quick wins and the longer term strategy. Experienced in the areas of product management, technical & non technical project management process improvement, campaign management and data analytics.

#### TECHNICAL SKILL

- Analytic Tool(s): ACL, SAS, IBM SPSS, Metabase, Clevertap, Google Analytics
- > Programming/Query Language(s): SQL [Redshift, Oracle, SQLite], Javascript, Jquery, Ruby, Python, R
- ➤ Other(s): Magento 2, Wordpress

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Product & Ecommerce, Qra** – Product & Ecommerce Lead (Business & Digital Product Owner) Sep 2021 – Present **Product & Ecommerce Lead – Ecommerce Business Owner**

- Responsible for end-to-end Ecommerce at Qra which includes multi-site management, product categorisation, stock availability, campaign management, multistore operations & delivery
- Responsible to define the overall business roadmap for Ecommerce to determine business and product development directions; Prioritise roadmap and work with interdepartmental teams for implementation & deployment
- Responsible for month-to-month data analysis for tracking site performance, sales & campaign performance and customer purchasing behaviour. Setup simple excel dashboard; BI dashboard to be considered for future phase
- ➤ Perform adhoc analysis for store vs online purchase to identify opportunities & gaps
- > Work with marketing & merchandising to align company level campaigns and to incorporate Ecommerce campaigns
- ➤ Manage 2 team members at HQ and collaborate with on ground operation staff at all stores for end-to-end delivery of Ecommerce experience

#### Product & Ecommerce Lead – Digital Product Owner

- Responsible for defining the overall company digital product roadmap; Inclusive of Ecommerce platform and other new digital platforms
- > Strategise and prioritise overall company roadmap based on impact, resource (people + cost) and process considerations to find the balance to map overall timeline
- > Responsible for sourcing, negotiating, liasing and managing vendor(s) for all digital product
- ➤ Hands on planning and execution for the entire product development process which includes business requirement gathering, product design (UI/UX), product backlog grooming & prioritisation, technical & non technical project management, multi vendor integration management, testing and deployment management

#### **Product Team, IKEA SEA & Mexico** – *Product Manager, Digital Solutions (Contract)*

Nov 2020 - Aug 2021

- Responsible for digital solution sourcing to implementation within IKEA SEA & Mexico. Sourcing of solutions includes both external and internally developed solutions.
- ➤ Work with key stakeholders to determine requirements and solution required within the region and develop product roadmap and manage backlog
- Work with interdepartmental teams and multinational teams for implementation of solution which includes developing and tracking key metrics to measure success of deployment of solution

#### **Growth Team, HealthifyMe** – Associate Product Manager

Jun 2019 - Nov 2019

- > Responsible for reviewing and driving growth for Malaysia and Singapore through the HealthifyMe app
- > Obtained feedback from users on key features and challenges faced to design new features/enhancements
- ➤ Work with tech and design team to develop product features (UI/UX) based on defined user stories
- > Developed dashboard to track key business metrics and performance of features

# **Transformation Team, U Mobile** – Assistant Manager/Product Owner(App)

Nov 2018 - Jun 2019

- > Responsible for new app development and the development of digital roadmap for unification of app and platforms
- ➤ Work with key stakeholders to setup project workflow and adoption of SCRUM for mobile app development

- > Host workshops with key stakeholders to identify key business requirements and to align requirements to develop long term app roadmap and developed user stories
- ➤ Defined key metrics and perform analytics using SAS, SQL Queries and IBM SPSS to identify and track historical metrics and develop reports and tracker of current app performance as basis for the new app

## Mentoring & Engineering Team, NEXT Academy – Mentor/Junior Engineer

Apr 2018 – Nov 2018

- Review course materials and work with mentor team to restructure course delivery and syllabus for effective learning. Key objective was to engage students and to train students to be self sufficient
- ➤ Mentored students on the following tech stack:
  - Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap | Backend: Ruby on Rails, SQL

### Customer Value Lifetime Management, U Mobile – Assistant Manager

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

#### Campaign Management System Implementation - Campaign Team/Product Owner

- ➤ Define business requirement and structure of campaign system through incorporating user and customer experience. Structure takes into consideration business objectives, customer experience, inter department user experience and feedback loop for campaign recalibration
- ➤ Identify key business objectives and perform campaign planning to define data frequency and data fields required for performance monitoring, customer segmentation and behavioral analysis
- ➤ Work closely with IT Project Manager and Vendors in ensuring requirements are met and identify workaround solutions where technical solutions are unable to meet business requirements
- > Review test plan to ensure completeness of positive and negative scenarios based on business requirements. Perform UAT and post deployment live test prior to official launch

### Acquisition, Upgrade and Loyalty Campaign – Campaign Team/Product Owner

- ➤ Identified key metrics based on business objective and developed report structure for high level monitoring and management reporting
- > Perform analytics using SAS queries and IBM SPSS on industry trends, customer segment and align findings with key business objective to identify campaign opportunities
- ➤ Plan and map the end-to-end customer journey whilst considering currently available resources, enhancements or process changes. For enhancement and campaign execution, considered both timeline and cost impact.
- ➤ Define business requirements and platform requirements where applicable for campaign execution. Review test plan and perform UAT and post deployment live test prior to launch
- Engage and work with cross-functional teams critical for execution of campaign

# **Enterprise Risk Services, Deloitte** – Senior Consultant

Nov 2011 - Oct 2015

#### Selected Project Highlights:

#### GST Project Management Office (Insurance Industry) - Team Lead

- Review the impact of GST to clients' environment through understanding clients' current business process and system functional aspects
- ➤ Enhance and develop new system and process workflows to incorporate GST requirements throughout clients' operations
- ➤ Monitor project progress and ensuring pre-set project timelines are met
- Perform data verification for validity of data crucial to GST computation
- > Perform recomputation to ensure accuracy of system computation and output based on the GST requirement

# ERP System Evaluation and Review (Water Services Industry) - Team Lead

- > Evaluated and identified areas for system enhancement in clients' existing ERP system through:
  - Identifying gaps in current ERP system and current business processes
  - Determining the risk and impact of existing gaps
  - Prioritising enhancement listing based on the impact to client and estimating the effort required
- > Conducted workshops to identify areas for enhancements and presented recommendations to management

### **EDUCATION**

**Data Science Certification Course** – 360DigiTMG, Malaysia

February 2020 – June 2020

Full Stack Web Development Quantum Degree – NEXT Academy, Malaysia

January 2018 – March 2018

**Bachelor of Commerce** – *University of Victoria, Canada* 

 $September\ 2009-August\ 2011$ 

**American Degree Program** – Taylor's University College, Malaysia

January 2007 – August 2008